457 Glenhill Circle Red Bank, TN 37415 jstocksdale@gmail.com 423-598-6212 Rafikisystems.com/stocksdale

Vision

Web Developer, Educator, Data Analyst, and Technology Implementer passionate about positively impacting the world – whether by encouraging and improving thinking, research and problem solving in the classroom, or by building and utilizing appropriate technology to enhance productivity, enable better decision-making, and improve life.

Significantly concerned about environmental, educational, and economic issues.

Visionary, compassionate, creative, hard-working learner best at big picture tasks, but willing to do almost any task to make a project succeed.

Skills

WEB/SOFTWARE DEVELOPER/PROGRAMMER

- 35 years of programming, design and development experience with numerous languages and technologies (java, vb, c++, c, access, progress, jquery)
- Most recent projects include extensive utilization of:
 - SQL, ANGULAR, DART, C#, SCSS, GitHub, Javascript, HTML
- Comfortable learning new languages and technologies
- Especially enjoy the intersection of design, programming, and vision

EDUCATOR/CURRICULUM DEVELOPER

- 35 years teaching at primary, secondary, and tertiary levels:
 - Computer/technology courses: (AP/Programming, Office, Design/Visual Communications, Adobe Products, Web Development)
 - Social Sciences (Psychology (AP), Current World Issues Government/Economics, Model United Nations)
 - o Mathematics (Algebra 1, 2, Pre-Calculus, Junior High)
- Student Academic Support (K-12), Tutoring, Mentoring, Advising
- Curriculum Development Communications and Information Technology department and course creation and Current World Issues course design
- Vision/Concern/Passion for academically challenged students and for appropriate use of educational technology

DATA ARCHITECT

- Very comfortable designing Relational Databases especially creative data organziation for better applications and analysis
- Designed unique and powerful open source "Graph" Database "on top" of SQL Server featuring a powerful permissions model and flexible, rapid development

DATA ANALYSIS

- Enjoy statistical analysis, especially identifying essential research questions.
- Growing comfort with R

TECHNOLOGY IMPLEMENTER

- Deployed various technologies for budget-concious schools and businesses with unique roll-out issues
- Best learning experience has been initiating, deploying and improving 10+ year one-to-one laptop/tablet program (including pre-iPad tablet design)

Page 2

Work History

RAFIKI SYSTEMS - Chattanooga, TN

2016 – Present

• Startup developing school software (AngularDart, C#, SQL) - originally for RVA

SODDY DAISY HIGH SCHOOL – Soddy Daisy, TN

Jan 2019 – Present

Teacher (Algebra 1 and Algebra 2)

RIFT VALLEY ACADEMY - Kijabe, Kenya

1990 – December 2018

Teacher (psychology, computer science, math, economics/current issues),
Software Developer, Technology Coordinator, Guidance Director, Student
Academic Support Coordinator, Department Head, Dorm Parent

COMPUTER HORIZONS - Chattanooga, TN

1997 – 1998

Consultant/Software Developer (Access and SQL Server databases)

GEORGIA DUCK AND CORDAGE MILL - Atlanta, GA

1991-1994

Consultant/Software Developer (Visual Basic, Progress, Paradox, SQL)

BEN & JERRY'S OF INDIANA – Indianapolis, IN

1989-1990

• Management and Point of Sale Implementation

INSTRUCTIONAL COMPUTER EQUIPMENT – Indianapolis, IN

1983-1988

 Software Developer (C) – created graphics editor (pre-Photoshop days) used by Herron School of Art, and web-like (pre-web days) tools for teachers to create interactive curriculum

BATTENBERG AND ASSOCIATES - Indianapolis, IN

1984-1988

Education and Business Technology Consulting and Development

TAYLOR UNIVERSITY - Upland, IN

1981-1983

Student Information System development

INDIANA VOCATIONAL AND TECHNICAL COLLEGE - Marion, IN

1982-1983

• Instructor – Introduction to Computer Science and Programming

Education

GEORGIA STATE UNIVERSITY - Atlanta, GA

1994

MS Educational Psychology, 4.0 GPA

INDIANA UNIVERSITY - Indianapolis, IN

1990

• Teaching Certification (Mathematics K-12)

TAYLOR UNIVERSITY - Upland, IN

1983

 BA Mathematics, Psychology (minors: Computer Science, Political Science), magna cum laude

Life

30 YEARS LIVING/WORKING/SERVING IN AFRICA

MARRIED TO SUSAN SINCE 1991, 2 KIDS, 19 AND 21, 2 DOGS

 $Hobbies \ include \ photography, \ hiking, \ coffee \ roasting, \ wood \ work, \ reading, \ learning, \ travel$

EXTENSIVE TRAVEL BY BICYCLE THROUGH US, EUROPE, AFRICA, 25+ COUNTRIES

VOLUNTEER TEACHER, MISSIONARY, TUTOR, MENTOR, CONSERVATIONIST, PROGRAM DEVELOPER

PERSONAL GENERAL CONTRACTOR FOR COTTAGE/RETREAT CENTER IN AFRICA.

Willing to travel, willing to work remotely, prefer team work